MALCOLM GOMES

Email: malcolmgomes0@gmail.com

CAREER OVERVIEW

I am a 4th year computer science student pursuing a career in the field of software development and data science. Throughout my university life, I have gained experience with the fundamental concepts of programming and computer science. I am particularly interested in Machine Learning and its applications in different fields.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Web Developer

Sept 2018 - Dec 2018

Review Board - Toronto, Canada (Remote work)

- Used Backbone.js and LESS to improve the user experience of the Review Board tool.
- Used the Jasmine framework to create JavaScript unit tests and perform test driven development (TDD).
- Collaborated with team to coordinate work on a new interface for an existing web form.

Web Development Assistant

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Ministry of Community Safety and Correctional Services – Toronto, Canada

- Used PHP, JavaScript, and WordPress to develop new features for existing web applications.
- Used WordPress to create and update content on internal intranet site.
- Used Microsoft Word and Visio to create documentation on the use of created web applications and software.

Library and Information Management Assistant May 2017 – Aug 2017 Ministry of Finance - Toronto, Canada

- Used PHP and JavaScript to create and update web pages on intranet site.
- Use Microsoft Office to analyze and annotate documents.
- Created spreadsheets and macro scripts for Excel spreadsheets to execute daily tasks.
- Worked in a collaborative environment on a team project to optimize and improve the workflow of other colleagues in office.
- Performed presentations of projects to colleagues and employees.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, C, JavaScript, Visual Basic, VBScript, MySQL Web Tools: HTML, CSS, PHP, Node.js, Backbone.js, Bootstrap, jQuery Operating Systems: Windows, GNU/Linux Development Tools: Git, Github, Visual Studio Experience with Machine Learning algorithms and techniques.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science (4th year)

Ryerson University - Toronto, Canada

AWARDS

Dean's List

2016 - 2017, 2017 - 2018